<!--
  ~ Copyright (c) 2026 Luis Paolo Pepe Barra (@LuisPPB16).
  ~ All rights reserved.
  -->

<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.projectsapo</id>
    <name>Project Sapo</name>
    <vendor email="ironkrozz@gmail.com">Luis Pepe</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
    A smart vulnerability scanner for your project dependencies.

    Project Sapo integrates directly into your IDE to detect security vulnerabilities in your Gradle and Maven dependencies.
    It leverages the OSV.dev database to provide real-time alerts and detailed remediation advice without leaving your workflow.

    <h2>Main Features</h2>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Automated Scanning:</b> Detects vulnerabilities in Gradle and Maven projects automatically.</li>
        <li><b>Real-time Alerts:</b> Get instant notifications about security risks in your dependencies.</li>
        <li><b>Detailed Reports:</b> View comprehensive vulnerability details, including summaries, severity, and fixed versions.</li>
        <li><b>Integrated Tool Window:</b> A dedicated "Project Sapo" tool window for managing and reviewing scan results.</li>
        <li><b>Direct References:</b> One-click access to official security advisories (CVE, GHSA, etc.).</li>
        <li><b>Visual Indicators:</b> Clear visual cues for safe vs. vulnerable packages.</li>
    </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <ul>
            <li><b>Initial Release:</b> First public release of Project Sapo.</li>
            <li><b>Gradle & Maven Support:</b> Full support for parsing dependencies from both Gradle and Maven build systems.</li>
            <li><b>OSV.dev Integration:</b> Connects to the Open Source Vulnerabilities database for up-to-date security info.</li>
            <li><b>Interactive UI:</b> Added a dedicated Tool Window with sorting, filtering, and detailed HTML reports.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.idea.maven</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow id="Project Sapo"
                    secondary="false"
                    icon="/icons/pluginIcon.svg"
                    anchor="bottom"
                    factoryClass="com.projectsapo.ui.SapoToolWindowFactory"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>